芬兰欢迎您
詹姆斯·梅
理查德·哈蒙德
杰牛丽·克拉克森
翻译
卡卡 李总
OckRazor  佳东 Oliver
校对
卡卡 OckRazor  清野过客 RN
时间轴
框 RN
大家好
Hello, everybody.
你好吗
How are you? How are you?
谢谢 很高兴见到你们 谢谢你们的到来
Thank you. Good to see you. Thank you for coming.
外面真冷
Cold out there!
太冷了
That is cold.
各位好
Hello, everybody!
你们好
Hello!
欢迎来到 The Grand Tour
Hello. Welcome to The GrandTour.
圣诞快乐
Happy Christmas.
这周 我们来到了
This week, we are coming -
如果你能看到窗外正下着淅淅沥沥的小雨
if you can see through the drizzle dribbling down the windows -
这里是斯堪的纳维亚
from Scandinavia.
哦耶
Oh, yeah.
当然 这里
This, of course...
这里是那些阴郁戏剧的故乡
This, of course, is the home of those gloomy dramas
在这里一个穿着套头毛衣的怪女人
where a weird woman in a jumper
盯着湖面看了六小时
solves a murder
然后破了一起谋杀案
by staring at a lake for six hours.
这很有可能变成
This will probably be the jolliest programme
自从四个葬礼和一个葬礼以后
to come out of this neck of the woods since...
原电影名为《四个婚礼与一个葬礼》
这个地方最欢脱的节目
Four Funerals And A Funeral .
是的
- Yeah.
那是瑞典的爱情喜剧
Swedish rom-com that was. Erm...
当哈利射了莎莉
When Harry Shot Sally .
原著：《当哈利碰上莎莉》
非常滑稽
Oh, a laugh a minute.
戴珍珠项链的少女 不对
The Girl With The Pearl Necklace. No.
注:可能指爱情动作片
-那是另外一种斯堪的纳维亚电影  -真的假的
-That's another sort of Scandinavian film. -Really?
是的
Yeah.
特别要强调的是
Anyway, specifically,
我们深入芬兰 这里在北极圈内
we are deep inside the Arctic Circle in Finland.
这就对了 而芬兰
There you go. And Finland, of course...
芬兰无疑是所有现任赛车手的故乡
Finland, of course, is home to every single racing driver currently...
-怎么了 -什么 所有人吗
-What? -What, all of them?
好吧 除了尼科 罗斯伯格 他是芬兰人
Well, apart from Nico Rosberg, who is Finnish,
老罗斯伯格是芬兰人
小罗斯伯格生在德国 拥有多国国籍
但是不知道出于什么原因 宣称他是德国人
but, for some reason, claims he's German.
他为什么要这样 我真搞不懂
Why does he do that? I have no idea.
还有谁是芬兰人
Who else is there, then?
有米卡 萨罗
Well, there's Mika Salo,
米卡 哈基宁  基米 莱科宁
Mika Häkkinen, Kimi Räikkönen.
等等 这些都同一个名字的不同拼法吧
Hang on, they're just anagrams of the same name, aren't they?
下面再说拉力车手
Then you've got rallying.
托米 马基宁  蒂莫 马基宁
There's Tommi Mäkinen, Timo Mäkinen,
尤哈 坎库宁  阿里 瓦塔宁
Juha Kankkunen, Ari Vatanen.
更多的重组词
More anagrams.
坑卡 万科宁
Kinky Wankinen.
注：JC瞎编名字
曼卡 盘他宁
Manky Pantiden.
真有吗
Really?
我有些不知所措了
I'm getting slightly carried away now.
说真的 我昨晚查了维基
Seriously, I went on Wikipedia last nigh
想找一些非赛车手的芬兰名人
to look for famous Finns who aren't racing drivers.
这是我列出来的
Put up the list I found.
我还注意到
And I noticed something
他们都是男的
they're all men.
所有都是
All of them.
有任何有名的芬兰女人吗
Are there any famous Finnish women?
芬兰人民们
Finnish people?
他们也不知道 说不出来
Nobody thinks so. They're all...
我知道为什么
I know why, OK?
那是因为所有的芬兰女人 在19岁的时候
It's because all Finnish women, at the age of 19,
都会前往英国成为互惠生
move to England to be au pairs.
这几年我给我的孩子们
I actually had three Finnish au pairs
找过三个芬兰互惠生
over the years for my children.
-真的吗 -是的 这很有趣
-Did you? -Yeah. It was always funny.
你到希斯罗机场去接你的新互惠生
You'd go to Heathrow airport to pick up your new au pair,
而且总是一群三十多岁的父亲们
and there'd always be a row of 30-something
排成一列在门前
fathers waiting at the gate
等着他们的斯堪的纳维亚互惠生们出来
for their Scandinavian au pair to come out.
有一年我永远不会忘记
And there was one year I've never forgotten.
有一个壮如驼鹿的人走了出来
This huge moose lumbered out of the door,
我旁边的人看了看他的接机牌然后说
and the man next to me looked at his piece of paper and went
天啊 饶了我吧
"Oh, for God's sake!"
这可不好
That's not good.
-我们可以继续节目了吗 -好主意
-Shall we get on with the show? -Yes, good idea.
因为今晚 在我们这档汽车节目里
Because tonight in our television programme about cars...
我吃了点切达奶酪
I eat some cheddar.
理查德说他不想吃
Richard says he doesn't want any.
我不想吃奶酪
I don't want cheese.
詹姆斯拿一辆福特GT40和法拉利P3比
And James compares a Ford GT40 to a Ferrari P3.
冲啊
Avanti!
但首先 如果你是在美国收看节目
But first, if you are watching this in America,
你可能会很惊讶的听到
you may be amazed to hear
福特野马没有在英国正式发售过
that the Ford Mustang has never been sold, officially, in the UK.
但现在不一样了 因为福特决定要将
Well, until now, because Ford has now decided
最新款的野马在英国发售
that the latest Mustang will be sold in the UK
配备V8引擎和右座驾驶
with a V8 engine and right-hand drive.
恩 这让我们这位美国同事
Mm, and this has made our other resident American
非常开心
very happy.
事实上他过于兴奋了
He was so excited, in fact,
当第一辆右舵野马
that when the first right-hand-drive Mustang
到达英国伦敦港的时候
arrived at the docks in the UK,
他专程去迎接了
he was actually there to meet it.
英国 伦敦港
它随时会来
It'll be here any minute.
来了 准备好了吗
That is it. Are we ready?
终于等到了 它落地了
This is the moment. It's touched down!
走起
Go, go, go!
这曲子有点太阴郁了吧
Look, it's a bit gloomy, isn't it?
不适合作为欢迎曲
It's not very welcoming
换首欢快一点的
Have you got anything more upbeat?
算了算了算了
Forget it! Forget it! Forget it!
算了吧
Forget it.
我太激动了 快尿出来了
I'm so excited, my tinkle is fizzing.
哦耶
Oh, yeah!
哦 抱歉了
Oh. Sorry about that.
我们实在是太没用了
We really are useless over here.
所以二战的时候才需要你们帮忙
It's one of the reasons we needed your help in the war.
首先 我决定
I decided that, first of all,
要带新野马四处转转
I'd show the new Mustang around,
所以我直奔伦敦
so I headed for London...
也就是英国的首都
which is the capital city.
这是伦敦塔桥
Ah, now, this is Tower Bridge.
有趣的是 它非常古老
Interesting. It's very, very old.
但是它能完全的折叠成一半
But it folds completely in half
早年间 马车也会从这过
so that, in the old days, the horses could go through.
这里是国会大厦
Now, that's the Houses of Parliament,
里面住着的都是傻瓜
which are a series of houses in which we keep all our idiots.
那个钟 叫大本钟
That clock thing, that's Big Ben.
我知道对你来说不算"大"
I know it's not what you call big
但不能只叫它"本“啊
but... but we couldn't just call it Ben.
这是和平纪念碑
And that is the Cenotaph,
用来纪念那些为国捐躯的烈士们
where we remember those who died fighting for us.
这里要开慢点
Slowing down a bit here.
以示尊重
Show some respect.
这个不知道是什么
No idea what that is
纳尔逊纪念柱
今天早上还没有呢
It wasn't here this morning.
那是一个骑自行车的人 你要特别小心
A cyclist, you want to be careful of those.
那种生物特别暴躁
Small but very angry creatures.
那是一支军队
That's the army.
当年就是他们朝白宫开了枪
They're the ones who shot at your White House.
真不好意思
Sorry about that.
逛完所有景点之后
Having seen all of the sights,
我们开出了城
we headed out of town
我终于可以放开手脚了
so I could do this.
就是这样
There it is.
这就是让英国
That is the soundtrack
朝思暮想了51年的声浪
that Britain has been missing for 51 years -
真正的美国V8肌肉车
real American V8 muscle.
大洋彼岸的我们不造这样的车
We just don't make cars like this on our side of the pond.
所有那些懒惰而又坚定的扭矩
All that lazy-but-determined torque.
在任何档位和速度下都能爆发
Squeeze the throttle in any gear at any speed...
它的畅销是必然的
...and there's an inevitability to the way it moves off.
这就像和太阳系掰手腕
It's like arm wrestling a solar system
你必输无疑
you're gonna lose.
感觉好奇怪
It is weird...
坐在右边开野马
driving a Mustang from this side.
就好像在结婚五十年之后
It's like suddenly changing your mind after
突然换到床的另一边睡一样
50 years of marriage and sleeping on the other side of the bed.
而且开着一辆仅售37000英镑
It's also weird driving a car with a big V8,
巨大的V8引擎 倒车影像
reversing camera, air-conditioned seats,
座椅通风
rain-sensing wipers
以及感应雨刷的车也很奇怪
that you can buy for £37,000.
这是宝马M4一半的价钱 一半
That's half of what you'd pay for a BMW M4. Half.
这时我们已经完全进入了市郊
Once we were in the countryside proper,
继续我们的观光之旅
I continued my sightseeing tour.
看 我把你的标志画在了小山坡上
Look, I've drawn your badge on a hill.
那个是杰里米画的
Jeremy did that one.
抱歉啦
Sorry.
最终我们到达了巨石阵
Eventually, we arrived at Stonehenge.
看呐 你会很吃惊地发现
That, you'll be amazed to learn,
这是个古代的日历
is an ancient calendar.
或者是块表 或者是教堂
Or a clock. Or a church.
我的英国一日游
My tour of Britain was then interrupted
被一位不速之客打断了
by an unwelcome arrival.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我是来提醒你
Well, I have come to remind you -
因为你显然已经忘了
cos you've obviously forgotten,
也因为你满脑子浆糊
cos you're too giddy -
我们在英国不需要野马
that we have no need for the Mustang in Britain.
如果我们想买一辆
Because if you want to spend,
价格在3万到3万5英镑 讲究速度的福特
what, £30,000-£35,000 on a fast Ford,
买福克斯RS啊
you'd buy a Focus RS
再合适不过了
cos that was designed for here.
不 以前在英国是只好买那个
No, you'd settle for that in the UK
因为买不到野马 但现在不同
because you couldn't buy this, but now you can.
就是这样
That is the point.
你会穿皮套裤吗
Would you wear chaps?
不会 因为我们有正经的裤子
No, because we have trousers.
你会穿牛仔靴
What about cowboy...
噢你已经穿上了
Oh, you are. Cowboy boots.
很恰当啊 我在迎接它
Well, it's appropriate. I'm welcoming...
听着 我不是喜欢美国的一切
Listen, I don't want everything from America
我只是爱野马
I just want the Mustang.
-蠢货 -不是 美国
-Stupid. -No, America--
野马并不适合这里
It wasn't designed for here.
-你会戴毡帽吗 -不会
-Would you wear a Stetson? -Well, no.
天太冷了 我戴顶毡帽吧
"It's cold out, I'll wear a Stetson."
不 你会戴毛绒帽
No! You wear a bobble hat.
这辆车就是毛绒帽
That's a bobble hat.
对了 等一下
Oh! No, hang on.
-我刚想起来 -怎么了
-I've just realised. -What?
哎 我不想再跟你说话了
Erm... I-I don't want to talk to you any more.
总而言之
Anyway...
总之 我们一会儿再继续
Anyway, we shall pick that up later on.
但现在是时候降档
But right now it's time to drop it a cog
左拐进入唠嗑街了
and hook a left into Conversation Street.
-严肃点 -这很正经的
-Serious.- It's serious.
这就是很正经的东西
It is serious stuff, this.
现在听好了 我们在英国经常听说
Now, look, in Britain we are always being told
北欧人开车很厉害
that the Scandinavians are brilliant at driving,
这也难怪
and that's because they would be
因为他们经常会遇到积雪路面
because they have to deal with all that snow.
他们厉害的原因就是因为经常撞车
Mm, they're brilliant because what they do most of all is crash.
你说的太对了 事实证明
Well, you're absolutely right, as it turns out,
我拿到了一些有意思的数据
cos I've got some interesting statistics here. Erm...
在英国 车祸的死亡率为1.2%
In Britain, 1.2% of accidents result in fatalities.
而在芬兰 恐怕是5.1%
Here, I'm afraid, it's 5.1%.
嗯 不光是芬兰人
Yeah, and it's not just the Finns, either,
我这么说有点莽撞
if I may be so bold.
我们的资深国际制片人
Our Senior International Producer -
这就是他的职位
that's his job title -
前几天来到了芬兰
came over to Finland the other day,
在机场租了辆宝马
rented himself a BMW at the airport -
注:宝马多为后驱车 雪天易滑
不是福特也不是欧宝 而是宝马
not a Ford or an Opel,you'll note, a BMW -
在他前往这里的时候
and on his way to the location here,
发生了这样一幕
this happened.
他确实翻车了
He did! He did!
我说他曾是资深国际制片人
When I say he's our Senior International Producer,
现在已经降级为初级国际制片人了
he's now our Junior International Producer.
-我们初级本地制片人 -嗯
-Our Junior Local Producer.-Yeah.
非常本地 准确的说是文具柜
Very local. Specifically,the stationery cupboard.
-他能胜任 -他也只能负责这个了
-He can produce that.-That's all he's in charge of.
他是怎么开翻的
How did he do that?!
问题是 我不明白
The thing is, what I don't understand is
芬兰人为什么要开那么快
how the Finns manage to go fast enough
还以各种方式撞车
to have a crash of any sort at all,
因为这里的超速罚金相当高
because the speeding fines here are insane.
我说的是真的
They're means tested,
前一阵有人在限速48km/h
which means a guy here recently
的地方开到了78km/h
was caught doing 49mph through a 30 zone
结果他被罚了11.2万欧元
and he was fined 112,000 euros.
这只是张超速罚单啊
That's a speeding fine!
芬兰真的罚得这么狠吗
Are they really that high in Finland?
真的假的
They are?
11万
A hundred and twelve...
11万2千
112,000.
想象一下他收到罚单时的表情
-Imagine getting that in the post!
有意思的是
Well, it's interesting.
实际上 芬兰首相最近说
Actually, there was a Finnish minister recently said
政府很需要那些超速罚单
that the government needs those speeding fines
来平衡那些负债
to balance the books,they said.
他们甚至说 超速有利于国家经济发展
They actually said, "Speeding is good for the country."
这其实就是
That is actually what...
对于每个国家来说都是如此
Because it is. Every country.
嗯 我们也该采纳这点
Right. We should adopt that.
-超速好处大大的 -是你们的社会责任
-Speeding is good for you.-It's your social duty.
-咱们再聊会啊 -哦 好啊
-A bit more conversation for you.-Oh, good!
我觉得除了劳斯莱斯
I think, with the exception of Rolls-Royce,
现在沃尔沃的内饰做的是最好的
Volvo now make the best car interiors of anybody.
他们做得确实非常出色
They do. They're very, very good.
不得不说 我同意
I don't like to,but I agree with you.
我前段时间开过新款S90
because I went in the new S90 the other day
内饰真的非常棒
and the interior is superb.
-我们这里有张图 -对 就是这款
-We've got a picture of it here.-Yes, that one.
他们用的都是淡色
They use pale colours.
座椅 地毯
They've got pale-coloured seats, pale-coloured carpets
木饰条都是淡色的
pale wood,
给人感觉明亮 通透且宽敞
and that makes it feel light and airy and spacious.
唯一的问题是 在这样的车里
The only problem is that in one of those
你没法吃梦龙巧克力冰淇淋
you couldn't enjoy a chocolate Magnum ice cream.
无所谓 我不吃冰淇淋
It's all right,I don't eat ice cream.
这事情可以判断你是不是直男
It's something to do with being straight.
什么 怎么了
What? What?
你们为什么要鼓掌
Why are you applauding him?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你是说 喜欢冰淇淋的就是
Are you saying everyone who likes ice...?
冰淇淋有点那个 你懂的
Ice cream is a bit,you know....
你是说所有的小孩都是同性恋
You're saying all children are homosexual?
不 我是说
No, but...
小孩吃没关系
There's nothing wrong with it,
但是一个成年男人吃冰淇淋 真有点那个
but a grown man eating an ice cream,you know, it's a bit...
我宁愿吃这个也不愿吃那个
it's that way rather than that way.
就是
It is...
欢迎进入理查德 哈蒙德的脑子里
Welcome to the inside of Richard Hammond's head.
我很正常的 我不信你不明白我什么意思
I'm right. I can't believe you can't see that.
很简单的事 就在你眼前摆着
It's easy.It's in front of you.
你能在车里吃蛋筒冰淇淋
You could enjoy a 99 in there.
-你是说69吗 -不是
-You mean a 69?-No...
注: 此处很污 自己领会
有冰淇淋杯的那种
Ninety-nine.
但是你没法吃巧克力棒
But you couldn't have the chocolate thingy.
-这不结了 -不是 我是说带巧克力的东西
-My case rests!-No, the chocolate thing!
-你看看 -你知道我说的是什么
-Exactly!-You know what I mean.
不是 当你开着沃尔沃
No,but if you had that Volvo,
你可以吃一根香草梦龙
you could have a white magnum...
-没错 -或者雀巢的奶油棒
- True.- ...or a Milky Bar.
嗯 但是绝对不能吃威化
Yeah,but not a Double Decker.
雪花巧克力更糟糕吧
Well, a Flake is worse.
不 威化更糟糕
No, Double Decker's worse.
威化
Double Decker...
你们知道威化是什么吗
Do you all know what I mean by the Double Decker?
一种包裹着巧克力的甜食
It is unique among chocolate confectionery items.
开车的时候咬一口
Take a bite as you're driving along,
就咬这么点 好了
and a bit about this big, OK,
它会悄无声息的碎掉
silently breaks away...
落在你两腿中间
...goes down between your legs
然后融化
and melts.
当你从车里出来的时候
So when you get out,
每个人都会觉得你拉裤子了
everybody thinks you've had some kind of trouser accident.
那些大块的棕色斑点
This big brown stain right...
-我懂你的意思 -确实这样
-I know what you mean.-It does happen.
雪花巧克力更糟糕好吧
A Flake is worse.
没有 真不是
No, it just isn't!
它的广告就说了 "最最脆的巧克力"
A Flake is advertised as "the crumbliest,flakiest chocolate".
所以它最糟糕了
-It is worse.
这算是唠嗑街的热门话题了
This is a hot topic on Conversation Street.
确实是
It is!
我觉得必须解决这个问题
I think we should settle it here and now.
我要到咱们的旅行箱里
I'm going to go into our travelling box.
我们的移动巧克力甜品店
Our travelling box of chocolate confectionery
然后
and I'm going to...
咱们来比一比吧 好吗
Let's settle it with a competition, yes?
给你詹姆斯的雪花巧克力
I'm gonna give you James's Flake
你吃威化
and you the Double Decker.
我把这张纸翻过来
I'll turn that over, so then you'll see
你就能看到我会掉多少渣子了
how much spills off as I eat the Flake.
-其实没那么多 准备好了吗 -这真是太科学了
-Not much. Right, ready?-This is scientific.
开始吧 哎呦 已经有些碎成渣了
Here we go. Oh.Some of it's already crum...
这块算作弊
This is cheating, this one.
好吧 你把渣子清理出来
OK, no,clear away the debris.
不是 我的 我的天啊
No, I need to... Jesus!
这算是你吃的
-That's part of eating it!-It isn't part of eating it!
才不是 我还没开吃呢
I haven't even begun.
-但是你都拆开包装了啊 -闭嘴
-But you've got to unwrap it.-Ssh!
作弊
Cheat.
-怎么了 -杰里米 你记得广告画面吗
-What?-Jeremy,you know that advert?
有个姑娘
Girl in...
有个姑娘在一片深红色的田地里
Girl in the the field of poppies
我们现在可没看到
we're not seeing that right now.
-我看到了 -我可没有
-I am.-I'm not.
好了 准备好了吗 看着
Right, ready? Watch this.
他要咬了 他的第一口
He's going in. First bite.
哇 掉下来了好多巧克力
Oh, it's a big fall of chocolate!
-嗯 -这可真是掉了不少
Mm.- It's a heavy sprinkling,that.
这也就一点巧克力渣子而已
That is just a light dusting of chocolate.
-一点渣子 好吧 -詹姆斯该你了
-A light dusting, yeah, OK.-Right, James May.
现在镜头转向詹姆斯 梅和他的威化
Moving over to James May and his Double Decker
非常激动 不是吗
This is exciting, isn't it?
这真是个伟大的汽车节目
-This is a great car programme.
开创性的一举 嗯
Groundbreaking stuff, yeah.
-大家安静 -我简直不能相信
-Quiet, please.-I can't believe...
我不相信没人做过这个测试
- I can't believe this hasn't been done before.
他要咬了 他咬了一口
He's going in.He's taking a bite.
看他咬的那一小口 看他的牙
His poor old gnash...His teeth!
灾难性的碎渣 胜负立判
It's a catastrophic fall!The clear winner...
威化确实比雪花巧克力还可怕
The Double Decker is worse than the Flake.
这是雪花巧克力的渣
There's the Flake.
那是威化的渣
There's the Double Decker.
那么 通过科学实验 我们证明了
So, there we are.Using science,we have now established...
如果你有辆沃尔沃
...if you've got a Volvo
千万别在车里吃威化
don't have a Double Decker.
永远也别吃
Ever.
也别吃冰淇淋 因为他 噢 还是算了
Or an ice cream, because he... Oh, no, forget it.
咱们稍微转移一下话题吧
Let's move a little further along Conversation Street,shall we?
几周前 亚马逊
Erm...A few weeks ago, Amazon,
给我们的节目做了个广告
they ran an advert for our show
我们还挺满意的
they ran an advert for our show, and we're rather pleased with it.
看到没有 囊括了所有的元素
See, it's got everything in.
-是啊 很有旅行的感觉 -那个标志
-Yeah, the sense of travel.-Logo.
-甚至还把羊放上来了 -是啊 非常完美
-And there's even the goat.-Yeah, no, that's perfect.
你想要的一切都在这里
-Everything you need there.
所有都有 请看大屏幕
All you need for the advert.It's on the screen.
非常棒 不是吗
It's good, isn't it?
是啊 你想看的所有东西都有
Yeah. All the essentials are there. Everything you need.
你该看到的都有
Everything you need to see.
其实吧
Actually...
所有重要的东西
All the important stuff.
哈蒙德 很抱歉
Hammond,I'm sorry to do this,
就在节目开播之前
but before the show launched
亚马逊又做了个广告
Amazon did another advert,OK,
有人在推特上发给我
which somebody sent to me on a tweet
当时我就截屏了
which I screen grabbed,
所以画质不好
so the quality's not good
但是我还是拿过来了
but I have brought it along.
来看一下
Here it is.
噢我的天哪
Oh, for God's sake!
我爱死他们市场部了
I like their marketing department a lot.
我觉得唠嗑街差不多可以结束了
I think that's enough Conversation Street,
让我们回到刚才的影片
so let's get back to our film.
好的 上回说到
Yes. Earlier on
我开着右舵的福特野马
I was in the right-hand-drive Ford Mustang,
带它游览我国的风景
showing it the sights around our country.
不幸的是 他出现了
Unfortunately, he turned up
试图证明
and tried to argue that the similarly priced
价格相近的福特福克斯更好
Ford Focus was a better bet.
嗯 没错
-Yeah, I did do that.
我的回应就是绝尘而去
-I responded by driving off
不跟你说话
refusing to talk to you.
有点没礼貌
A bit rudely, I thought.
不好意思 可这是我的影片
I'm sorry, this is my film
我的旅行
my tour of England,
我不想被他毁了
and I didn't want him spoiling it.
这辆车真是太棒了
This thing's bloody awesome.
听听他的吼叫声
Listen to that bellow.
车身深深的坐进了底盘上
This thing squats on its haunches
它就是为此而造的
This is what it's built to do.
每一次噼里啪啦砰砰磅磅的声音
Every crackle, pop and bang
都会通过每根神经直接传给我
is just connected to every synapse and sinew in me.
噢 不是吧
Oh, no.
这就好比第一次约会的时候
This is like a first date for me, and on a first date,
你不希望女孩的秃顶胖叔叔全程尾随
you don't want a fat,balding uncle tagging along.
所以我现在要做的就是 甩掉他
So what I'm gonna do now... is lose him.
接招吧 尝尝我的厉害
It's Hammer Time!Shock and awe!
邦德 大战 伯恩
It's Bond versus Bourne.
《007》《谍影重重》
他那辆排量5.0 而我只有2.3
He's got five litres.I've only got 2.3.
可他的速度有我2倍快吗 并没有
Is he going twice as fast?No, he is not.
前面是弯道
Corner coming up
开着野马再也不用担惊受怕了
There's no need to panic any more in a Mustang,
因为 野马史无前例的
because, for the first time,
装备了后独立悬挂
the Mustang has independent rear suspension.
这辆车的过弯速度
The cornering speeds this thing can achieve
令人不敢相信
beggar belief.
这车的抓地力怎么这么强
How does it grip that well?!
我正开着野马进行飞车追逐
I'm in a car chase in a Mustang.
我就是史蒂夫 麦奎因
I am Steve McQueen.
尝尝这招
Try that on.
我切换到了运动模式
I've got it in Sport Mode,
能让排气轰隆作响
which makes the exhaust pop and bang.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
油门到底
Flat out, yeah.
抓地力太惊人
And it still grips!
这车没必要加牵引力控制系统
What is the point of traction control on this thing?
就好像给修女戴贞操带一样没意义
It's like putting a nymphomania control on a nun.
噢 坏了
Oh, God!
他跑哪儿去了
Where's he gone?
这不可能 他开着那辆18世纪的老古董
How did he do that? How did he get away from me
是怎么甩掉我的
in something from the 18th century?
而且我还开着
Especially when I'm driving
一辆带涡轮增压的藤壶
what is basically a turbocharged barnacle.
藤壶:一种吸附力极强的海洋动物
这辆车拥有最精密的四驱系统
This has the most sophisticated four-wheel-drive system
谁都比不上
fitted to any car.
GTR的四驱都比不上它
Not even a Nissan GTR could live with this.
那辆野马就好比听着唐 亨利
The Mustang, well, that's for cruising down
唐亨利: 老鹰乐队主唱
在太平洋海岸公路上巡航
the Pacific Coast Highway,listening to Don Henley.
而这辆车就像是听着Clash乐队
This is for storming up the Stelvio Pass,
the Clash:著名朋克摇滚乐队
斯泰尔维奥山口公路:TopGear S10E01有出现
在斯泰尔维奥山口公路飞驰
listening to the Clash.
尽管如此新潮且充满高科技
But while it's a grippy,technological masterpiece,
但它依旧保留着祖辈的蓝领性格
it still has the blue-collar character of its ancestors.
它在很多地方
In many ways
都让我想起了当年的Escort Cosworth
this reminds me of the old Escort Cosworth
那可是辆伟大的车
and that was a great car.
我在90年代有一辆 我叫它Gary
I actually had one in the '90s. I called it Gary.
每天早上我打火 它会问候我
It started every morning and it always went
"今儿要去干嘛"
"Do you want some?!"
口气就像是长了雨刷的约翰 特里
It was just John Terry, really, with windscreen wipers.
约翰·特里：英超切尔西队队长
与此同时 在成功甩掉大猩猩以后
Meanwhile,having got rid of the ape,
我继续带着野马四处观光
I was back on my sightseeing tour.
这是我们的切达峡谷
This is our Cheddar Gorge.
很明显没有你们的峡谷大
Obviously it's not as big as your gorge.
科罗拉多大峡谷要更大一些
The Grand Canyon is bigger.
更长 更深 也更广阔
Well, it's longer and deeper... and wider.
但那里没有奶酪
Mm. But it doesn't have any cheese in it.
你别来烦我行吗
Why can't you just leave me alone?
我的意思是
I'm just saying
在美国 所有东西里都会加奶酪
everything in America comes with cheese
除了科罗拉多大峡谷
apart from the Grand Canyon.
然而这座峡谷却出产奶酪
Whereas this canyon does come with cheese
还很好吃
and it's delicious.
-你也吃点 -我不想吃奶酪
-Here, have some.-I don't want cheese.
比蒙特里杰克好吃多了
-It's better than Monterey Jack in a tube.
你毁了我的节目
-You're ruining this!
你才是呢 因为你在告诉所有人
No, you are, because you are telling everyone
野马比福克斯要强
that the Mustang is better than the Focus.
-本来就是 -并不是
-Well, it is.-It isn't.
-是这样 -不是
-It is.-No, it isn't.
听着 我并不是说福克斯很完美
Look, I'm not saying this is perfect
它确实不是
cos it isn't.
它开起来很颠
There's a vertical choppiness to the ride
这点很讨厌
which is annoying.
如果你把手机放在
If you put your phone in the phone holder
档把前面的槽里
in front of the gear lever
在加速的时候手机会飞到座椅下面
and then accelerate,it shoots under the seat.
你就再也见不到它了
You never see it again.
油箱实在是太小了
Petrol tank, way too small.
而且它的风格有点粗鲁
-And the styling is a bit...yobbish.
有点而已吗
-A bit?!
但是哈蒙德 看这里
But, Hammond, look at this.
没错 你说得对
Oh, yeah, you're right.
野马拥有半个世纪的历史
Half a century of Mustang history
传承和骄傲
heritage and pride,
却没有想到在门上加一块小塑料片
but it hasn't got a small plastic strip on the door
以防你笨手笨脚磕到门
in case you're a bit clumsy.
但这个设计太巧秒了 而且它还更快
No, it's brilliant, that. And... this is faster.
不 我的更快
Well, no, it isn't.
-我的快 -不 我的
-It is.-No, it isn't.
-就是我的快 -是我
-It is.-It isn't.
事已至此 我决定放弃我的行程
At this point,I decided to abandon my tour
到最近的机场
and head for the nearest airfield...
给大猩猩上一课
...to teach Clarkson a lesson.
好了 我有410匹马力
Right,I've got 410 horsepower -
比他要多100匹
that's 100 more than him.
而且我还有个福克斯没有的功能
But there's something else on here that's missing on his Focus,
叫做 弹射预备
and it's this - "line lock".
启动 按住OK键开始初始化
So, engage it.Press OK to initialise.
正在初始化 初始化完成
"Initialising.Initialising complete.
确认后踩住刹车启动
Firmly apply and hold brake to engage.
已启动 按OK键开始
Engaged. Press OK to begin."
我现在锁住了前轮制动
What that's doing is locking the front brakes,
这样就可以暖胎了
so I can warm up my tyres.
这个功能对那种人来说非常理想
Hm. That is an ideal feature
他们每天睁开眼睛就会想
for people who wake up in the morning and think
我觉得我的轮胎花纹太深了
"Do you know, I've got too much tread on my tyres."
哈哈 烧胎变得如此简单
Yeah!I'm doing that automatically!
太蠢了
What a moron.
暖胎完毕之后
With my tyres warmed up,
我把车开到了起点线
I took my place on the start line.
好了 赛道模式 弹射起步
Right, race mode, launch control,
带超增压技术的涡轮
over-boost facility on the turbocharger,
四轮驱动
four-wheel-drive
以及一位拥有闪电反应的驾驶员
and a man with lightning actions at the wheel.
这辆车会像春天的羔羊一样蹿出去
This car is going to boing off the line like a spring lamb.
开启弹射起步 挂入一档
Launch control, first gear
我准备好了
and we're ready to go.
噢 他领先了
Oh, he's away first.
世界上最棒的弹射起步
The most incredible launch control in the world!
加油啊
Come on!
加油 杰里米 你就要赢了
Come on, Jeremy. Come on. You're winning.
追上他了
Oh, reeling him in!
不 不 这不可能
No, no, no! That's simply impossible!
谢谢他的参与
Well, bless him for trying.
我现在最不想看到的就是 他
Things I don't want to see right now - number one, him.
那个啥 我赢了
So er... I won, then.
-我知道 但你的车没有漂移按钮 -什么按钮
-Yes, but your car doesn't have a drift button.-A what?
-漂移按钮 -干嘛用的
-A drift button.-What does that do?
你按下漂移按钮之后
Well, you push it,and then,
过弯的时候就可以漂移
when you go round a corner,the car drifts.
-真的吗 -真的
-Does it?-Yeah.
你知道吗 我很想见识一下
You know, I'd love to see that in action.
-我想看你漂移 -没问题
-I'd love to see you doing that.-Yes.
-给我演示一下 我想看 -你在这儿看好了
-I'll watch. Yeah, show me.-You stay there.
有了它 就连詹姆斯 梅都能漂移
You will not... Even James May could drift this.
-我来也 -我等不及了
-Here we go!-I can't wait to watch.
看呐 女士们先生们
Check it out,ladies and gentlemen!
好好看看
Check it out!
我在漂移
I'm drifting.
你觉得怎么样 哈蒙德 瞧
What do you think of that, Hammond? Look at that!
哈蒙德
Hammond?
人呢
哈蒙德
Hammond!
怎么了 你不会怪我吧
What?You're not gonna blame me.
你跑哪儿去了
-Where did you go?
我走了 因为你太蠢
Well, I left you because you were being moronic.
-我没有 -你就是
-I wasn't!g-You were!
说实话 如果你能买得起
Seriously,who is going to buy
V8引擎的野马 谁会去买
a Ford Focus when,for the same money,
价钱一样的福克斯啊
you could havea V8-engine Mustang?
-没人 -什么
-No-one.-What?
没人会买福克斯 野马太有个性了
Nobody would. Mustang's got so much more character.
等一下 你同意我说的吗
Hang on.So, you agree with me?
当然了 如果让我选
Oh, God, yes! If I had the choice of those two cars,
我每次都会选择野马
I'd have the Mustang every day of the week.
所以你是毫无理由地毁了我的一天
So you ruined my day out for no reason at all?
可是给你的一天添堵 很有意思啊
I ruined your day out because it was fun...to ruin your day out.
-干得漂亮 -没错 对不住了
-Good work.-It was good work.Sorry about that.
现在该来看看这两辆福特
But anyway, we must now find out
在我们赛道上的表现了
how fast those Fords go round our track,
也就是说要把它们交给
and that, of course, means handing them over
我们的另一位美国同事
to our other resident American -
他觉得沐浴露基本上就是共产党
a man who thinks that shower gel is basically communist.
有请老美
It's the American.
他在那儿 看上去有点困惑
There he is, looking bewildered.
他出发了
And he's away!
听起来像是有一群老鼠堵在排气管里
It sounds like a bunch of goddamn mice in there.
他们为什么就不能用8个气缸呢
Why the hell don't they just start with eight cylinders?
我没见过这么奇怪的老鼠 他驶入了不直道
Strangest mice I ever heard, as he powers down the Isn't.
声浪听着不错
That is a good noise.
握着方向盘的两只胳膊就像是和这辆车较劲
Arms working the wheel like he's wrestling a drifter,
不过也确实如此
which, of course, he is.
这时他已经来到了留你名弯
And already he's at Your Name Here.
轮胎发出了尖叫 但依然牢牢抓着地面
Tyres squealing, but it's clinging on well,
然后上坡回到不直道
and now the climb back onto the Isn't.
这车的空间太小了
It ain't got no room in it.
没有放啤酒的地方
No place to put your beer.
我觉得他和我放在车里的东西有点不一样
I think he and I look for slightly different things in a car.
不管怎样 现在大力刹车
Anyway, now hard on the brakes
进入老奶房弯
as he turns into Old Lady's House.
在他的操控之下一切平稳
Yeah, he is dispatching that with no dramas,
现在他可以勇往直前
and now he can get the hammer down
通过颠簸路段来到变电箱弯
for the bumpy sprint to Substation.
看起来不错
Looking good.
四轮驱动的车会出现转向不足
Four-wheel-drive cars can, of course, understeer,
但在这里并没有出现
but... nope, not a whiff of it here.
干净利落地通过绵羊坡
And Field Of Sheep, tidy through there as well,
然后冲线了
and across the line.
我觉得他应该会喜欢这辆车
Now, I think he might enjoy this one.
的确如此 响胎起步
And he is wheel-spinning away!
这就对了 我爱美国肌肉车
All right! American muscle, baby!
5.0升的野马 这家伙可不好惹
5.0 Mustang - this thing is badass.
还有个大后备箱 可以装我的高尔夫球杆
It's got a trunk, place for my golf clubs.
带上我家娘们
Pack up the old lady
周末开车出去玩
go for the weekend somewhere in this thing,
想甩尾巴就能甩
and you can haul ass while you're goin'.
他说了些关于老女人和甩屁股的事
Something there about an old lady and hauling a bottom.
驶入不直道
Anyway, he's on the Isn't,
飞一般地冲进留你名弯
and he's flying into Your Name Here.
强大的野马让老美充满了活力
The mighty Mustang has filled the American with vigour,
这个弯他处理得异常简练
and he's being surprisingly tidy.
这才是美国人要的 我们就想烧胎
That's what us Americans want, we want to smoke the tyres.
甭废话 就该这么来
We want this thing to just get shit and get.
我实在不知道他在说什么 只听到了噪音
Literally no idea what he's on about. It's just a noise.
这车刹车贼强 说停就停
When this thing stops, man, it stops on a dime.
刹车特牛 一秒就停
"It'll stop on a dime and give you nine cents change" is what we say.
你根本没办法让他闭嘴
You really can't shut him up about this one.
好了 干净得通过了老奶房弯
Anyway, he is keeping it neat round Old Lady's House,
然后释放出V8的狂怒
and then unleashing that V8 fury
一路杀到了变电箱弯
over the rough stuff to Substation.
大力踩下刹车 准备90度左弯
Hard on the brakes, ready for the 90 left.
驶过绵羊坡
Blip it up to Field Of Sheep.
他来了
Here we go.
霸气地甩了车尾 冲线
Flurry of exuberance, and across the line.
就是这样
There we are.
好了 这是圈速榜
OK, here's the Lap Board.
我们先来看看福克斯的成绩
Let's have a look, first of all, where the Focus went.
在哪
So...
噢 在这儿
Oh, there it is.
比ST200快 并不意外
Faster than an ST200 - perhaps not surprising.
本该如此
Just as well.
现在看看野马的表现
Now let's bring up the Mustang.
噢
Oh!
这一点也不尴尬对吧
- That's not embarrassing, is it?
你 我还有老美都喜欢的车
The car that you, me, and the American all prefer
比欧洲血统的福克斯慢了很多
is quite a lot slower than the European Focus.
没错
Yes.
好了 听我说 我们继续节目吧
Anyway, listen,let's move on, shall we,
下面是 明星脑碰脑
to Celebrity Brain Crash.
听着
Now...
本周的嘉宾 不仅是我最喜欢的F1车手
our guest this week isn't just my favourite Formula One driver,
还是个芬兰本地小伙
he's also a local boy.
没错 他就是赛车界的话唠
Oh, yeah, this is the chatty man of motorsport,
注:说反话 莱科宁一向沉默寡言
根本停不下来先生
Mr Effervescent,
女士们先生们 有请基米 莱科宁
ladies and gentlemen, Kimi Räikkönen!
他来了
Here he comes.
我们一会儿要问他什么
What are we gonna ask him?
你问他什么都不重要
It doesn't matter what you ask him.
因为你根本得不到一个连贯的答案
It doesn't, because you won't get a coherent answer.
他没事吧
Is he all right?
等一下 噢不
No, hang on. Whoa!
-噢不 -又是这样
- Oh, no. - Not again.
是的 女士们先生们
No, he has, I'm afraid, ladies and gentlemen,
莱科宁因饮酒过量而死
literally drunk himself to death.
见鬼
Damn.
就是说 他来不成了?
- Does that mean he's not coming on, then?
当然 他肝中毒了
Well, his liver has failed
而且他正在北极圈冰冷的黄昏中
and he's now slowly solidifying
逐渐僵硬 所以没错 他来不了
in the freezing dusk of an Arctic night, so that's a no.
没事 无所谓
Yeah, but it doesn't matter.
其实有所谓 我还是挺喜欢他的
Well, it does, cos I actually rather liked Kimi.
不过我可以想出点其他事情
But I can think of something else we can do to fill the time.
是这样的 如果你现在
Here's the thing.Er... If you're watching this
正在收看这个节目 时间应该
on the day the programme is actually released,
已经是12月23日了
it is December 23rd.
距离圣诞节只剩两天
There are two days to go until Christmas,
如果你是个男人
and if you're a man
你应该还没买任何礼物
you won't have done any shopping yet.
-但是别担心 我们会帮助你的 -没错
-But don't worry,cos we've got your back.-Oh, yeah.
我们在线上线下四处搜罗
We have trawled the Internet and the shops
寻找送礼物的最佳思路
to find the best gift ideas.
这里是我们特意准备的GT圣诞小岩窟
Yes, and here, in our special Grand Tour Santa Land Grotto.
没错
Yeah.
布置得不错 很漂亮
Nice view. Nice everything.
是啊
Yeah. Er...
我们先从这个绝妙的托盘开始
We begin with this rather brilliant tray,
它显然是笔记本电脑和早餐的
which, apparently, is the ideal place to put your laptop
绝佳伴侣
or your breakfast.
这里有一张示意图
We have a picture of it in action here.
-等一下 -我觉得有几个问题
Hang on a minute!- I see a couple of problems with that.
-我也觉得 -接下来是什么
- I can too.- What else have we got?
我现在不怎么下国际象棋了
Well, now, the reason I don't play chess any more
因为移动棋子实在太累了
is it's just so exhausting to move the pieces around.
我懂你意思了
-I know what you mean.
把女王拿起来移动 太沉了
-Far too heavy, picking the Queen up and moving her.
但是没关系 法拉利解决了这个难题
But it's OK, because Ferrari has answered that problem with this.
一套轻量化的碳纤维国际象棋
- It's a lightweight, carbon-fibre chess set...
只需1400英镑你就可以带回家
...and it's yours for £1,400.
-多少钱 -1400英镑
-How much?! -£1,400.
有意思的是 不管多普通的东西
And that is the funny thing you take something ordinary,
只要上面挂个车标 突然就变贵了
write a car name on it, and suddenly it becomes expensive.
就拿这只玩具熊说 以我的了解
This bear, for example. I know about bears.
就是点人造纤维纺织品
It's an acrylic fibre,
填充点工业垃圾进去
stuffed with industrial waste.
只要2.75英镑
£2.75.
一旦穿上件本田T恤 就要10英镑了
But, because it's got a Honda T-shirt on, £10.
10英镑噢
£10.
对 但这可是本田熊啊
Yes, but it's Honda Bear!
或者
Or...
我好喜欢这个圣诞礼物 本田熊
I love that! On Christmas morning, Honda Bear!
我要跟它一起玩耍
I love following his adventures!
看看这个做工精美的
How about this lovingly crafted
我爱现代 枕套
"I love my Hyundai" pillowcase?
什么样的女人会愿意
What woman is ever going to leap into bed
和一个用这种枕头的男人睡觉
with a man whose pillows bear that legend?
哈蒙德 让我来告诉你是什么样的女人
OK, Hammond, I'll tell you exactly what woman.
愿意穿这种丁字裤的女人
The woman who would wear this thong,
它的正面写着
which has written lovingly on the front,
伊兰特
the legend Elantra.
太性感了
Erotic! Erotic!
我能这么说吗
Can I just say
给现代车主最好的礼物
the perfect Christmas gift for the Hyundai owner
应该是台宝马
is a BMW.
我们都发现品牌的东西
Well, yes, look, we realised that branding stuff,
都很贵
obviously there's some money in it,
而且来到了芬兰 我们就想到
so we thought, since we're in Scandinavia,
我们也该推出
we would launch
我们自己品牌的套头衫
our own range of car-branded Christmas jumpers.
-嗯哼 -对的
Mm-hm. - Oh, yeah. Yeah.
稍等一下 大家随便聊会儿天
- Talk among yourselves, everybody. Hold on a moment.
现在是试衣时间
This is modelling time.
我的是件翻领毛衣
Mine is a simple turtleneck.
非常非常暖和
Very, very warm
正面印着传奇的捷豹E-Type
bearing the name of a legend on the front.
是的 很特别 很有圣诞气息
I know, it's very special. Very Christmassy, yeah?
我的是一件很可爱的
- I have gone for a very cuddly...
很圣诞的开衫毛衣
...and Christmassy cardigan bearing the name,
正面印着我非常喜爱的尼桑GTR
as you can see, of a car I absolutely adore.
好了 现在看我的
Yeah, and here's the thing, OK.
我的是件圆领的
Mine is a crewneck, actually.
↓ PENIS：阴茎 ↓
为什么他们都在笑
Why is everybody...?
-你们干嘛鼓掌 -我也不知道
- Why are you applauding? - I don't know.
我觉得
I think...
-你们为什么 -是不是
-Why are you...? -Is it...?
因为观众都没见过我们穿毛衣吗
Is it because they haven't seen us in knitwear before?
不管怎么样
Anyway
我们还尝试做了一些GT的周边
we've had a go at making some Grand Tour-branded stuff.
-哦 是的 -但是
-Oh, yeah. -But here's the thing.
我们没有走寻常路 做些常用的东西
We haven't gone for the obvious stuff,
像套头衫 马克杯 雨伞这些
like jumpers and mugs and umbrellas.
我们做的 都是别人没想到的
We've gone for things that other people haven't thought of.
像这个
Things like this -
痔疮膏
haemorrhoid cream.
-人人都需要吧 -我不用
-We all need it. -I don't.
我也不用
No, I don't, either.
好吧 这是我的
Well, this is mine.
2.75英镑买的 但是现在贴上GT的标志
Bought it for £2.75, but now it's got Grand Tour on it,
就可以卖20英镑了
we could sell that for £20.
我来介绍些我们最棒的创意
I tell you what really good idea we've had erm...
那就是避孕套
is condoms, OK, which have been...
上面印着一些我们几个
well, they've been branded with well-known expressions
有代表性的口头禅
and phrases that we often say.
-我就用这个来展示吧 -哇哦
-I'm gonna demonstrate using this-- -Whoa!
你不要太自己为是了
You flatter yourself, sir!
-实事求是而已 -真的么
- Au contraire. - Oh, really?
我们把它套在擀面杖上
So we simply roll the condom over the rolling pin.
看这里有GT的标志
Here it is. There's the GT logo coming up.
另一边写着 这能有多难（硬）
And on the other side, "How hard can it be?"
我们很满意
We're very pleased.
对我这岁数的男人来说 挺硬了
Pretty damn hard, for a man of my age.
我们很满意这个创意
We're... We're very pleased with these.
很多我们的口头禅都能用上
Various of our slogans have been used.
我来展示一下我的
I'm going to put mine on this er...
用这个令人失望的小萝卜
disappointingly small carrot.
上面印着我的口头禅
Erm... And it bears one of my expressions.
-打不开 -别用嘴咬
-See, I can't-- -Don't bite it!
我撕不开包装
Well, I can't open the thing, can I?
不对 这边有可撕开的口
No, there's one of those little tear things.
亲爱的等等 马上就好
Hold on, love. I'll be with you in a minute.
不对 要这样
-No, it's--
这种时候你又不会在我身边
-You're not gonna be here to help me when I'm using it!
-说不准噢 -肯定不会
-You don't know! -I bloody do!
-我可能会在 -我确定你不会
-I might be. -I'm pretty sure you won't be.
好污 你搞定了吗(你进入吗)
That's quite the wrong thing to... Are you in?
-搞定了 等等 什么 -可以把眼镜还我吗
-Yeah, I'm... What?! -Can I have my glasses back?
-不 -不行 我要拿回我眼镜
-No. -No, I want my glasses back
趁它还没看到那些色情的东西
before you start messing around with sex things.
好的 让我来 等等 有点大了
Oh, right, let me... Oh, dear. It's a bit baggy.
我都用牙撕了
I've actually torn it with my teeth,
这样显得这句话再合适不过了
which makes the slogan on it quite appropriate, really -
"这样可不好"
"That's not gone well."
这么说吧 到目前为止
Can I just say, that is by far and away
这是我见过最不性感的东西了
the least erotic thing I have ever...
别说你对这个画面不熟悉
Don't tell me that's not an unfamiliar sight.
嘲笑大猩猩是小萝卜
对了 你也弄了一个吧
Oh, have you done one as well?
当然了 而且我提前戴好了
Of course I have. Very sensibly, I put mine on earlier.
哇哦
Whoa!
上面印着GT标志和我常说的
Branded with the GT logo and my own personal catchphrase,
我是第一个到的
"I was the first to arrive."
你是否厌倦了拥有两只功能健全的脚踝
Are you bored with having two fully functioning ankles?
如果是 请不要担心
Yes? Well, don't worry if you are,
因为今年圣诞节市场上充斥着
because this Christmas, the market is awash with products
许多可以弄伤脚踝的产品
designed specifically to break them.
比如这款 iBot-9
such as this iBot-9.
我还以为是个扫地机器人
I thought that was a vacuum cleaner.
不是 这玩意非常重
No, it's incredibly heavy
可能是里面装满了痛苦
because it's packed full of pain.
把这两个踏板打开
Basically, you put these things out on the side
站上去就可以动了
you stand and whizz about.
但是不用几秒
But within seconds of getting on
你就会摔倒在地 弄伤脚踝
you will be falling over and breaking your ankles.
很有可能
Probably so.
好的 还有这款可供挑选
Yes, and on the other hand, there are also these.
这个叫做风火轮
These are called the Rocket Skates.
仅售900英镑
They will cost you just £900,
保证能把你弄成半个残废
and they are guaranteed to power you straight to casualty.
是的
Yeah.
-不会的 没问题的 -一定会的
- No, they're fine. -No, they're really not.
我就不会 我可以穿上试试
-I'll be all right. I could have a go on those.
你们想看吗
-Who'd like to see that?
你自己说的
You said it.
真的 我真心觉得没问题
Seriously. I mean, honestly...
这能有多难
"How hard can it be?"
我就知道这擀面杖有用 可以用来
See, I knew it would come in handy. I can bludgeon...
-真的 让我试试 -上吧 哥们
-Seriously, I'll have a go. -Off you go, mate.
-好的 -我可以穿着鞋子套进去吗
- Yeah. - Can I wear my shoes in them?
跟滑雪靴一样吧
Are they like ski boots?
是的 杰里米 不过上面有轮子
Yes, Jeremy, apart from they've got wheels
而且你在室内
and you're indoors.
我是不会穿的
-I am not going near them.
帮我把脚放进去
Just put my foot in them.
我可不想
I don't want to!
我自己看不到
-I can't see what I'm...
我不想这样 好丢人
-It's degrading and unpleasant.
-我需要脱鞋吗
-Do I take my shoes off?
把你的蹄子放进来吧
-Put your great cloven hoof in there.
很合脚 你可以穿着去跳舞了
It fits! You can go to the ball.
好了 穿好了
There, you're in.
-非常感谢 -现在你该怎么办
-Thank you. -Now what are you gonna do?
你不会真的要试吧
You're not gonna do it!
-就这样吗 开始了吗 -还没有呢
-Is that it? Have you started? -Not yet.
我最好朝着另一边 对吧
I better face the other way, hadn't I?
看起来不错
Looking good.
这玩意很值啊
These are worth every...
多少钱来着 900镑
What will they cost, 900 quid?
-900英镑 -一分钱都没白花
-Nine hundred quid. -Literally every penny.
等等 站着别动
Wait, hold it there. Hold it there.
达西先生：《傲慢与偏见》主人公之一
小心点 姑娘们 达西先生来了
Look out, girls, Mr Darcy's arrived.
看起来不错
Looking good.
-太棒了 -哇哦
- Oh, this is brilliant. - Wow!
怪不得要叫风火轮
I can see why they're called Rocket Skates.
-快点啦 -我正在努力移动啊
- Come on, man. - Oh, God! I'm trying to move!
-向后靠 -怎么向后靠
Lean back! - What do you mean, "Lean back"?
像这样吗
Like that?
-杰里米 -怎么
-Jeremy? -What?
霍金穿上这个
Stephen Hawking would make a better job of these
走得都比你快
Rocket Skates than you have.
-好吧 -你要往哪儿去
-Right... -Where are you going?!
-你得把一只 -你还记得
- You've got to get one... - Do you remember...
哇哦 出大事了
Whoa! It's a disaster!
妈的 不好意思
Shit. Sorry.
别担心 杰里米 让我来救你
Don't worry, Jeremy. I will come and rescue on my...
我勒个去
Bloody hell!
我的天啊 它发疯了
Oh, my God. It's going mad.
嗯 好了
Erm... Right. Right.
把我的脚放这儿
-I put my foot on there.
救护车来的太快了
This is a really good ambulance service.
好了 别着急 马上就到
Yeah. Yeah. Don't worry, I'll be there in a minute.
没想到还真能用啊
I don't know that this works.
我又要摔了
I've gone again!
见鬼 我抽筋了
Shit! Now I've got cramp!
这真是个好东西 不过没关系
That was... That was a brilliant idea, but never mind,
我这里有一份最棒的圣诞礼物
because erm... I have a perfect Christmas present here.
可以通过手机遥控
You control this
把你的脸显示在这里
with your mobile phone and your face comes on it.
最棒的是 这意味着
And the brilliant thing about it is that it means
你可以邀请你最喜欢的名人到家里来
you can have your favourite celebrity
和你共进圣诞午宴
round to your house for Christmas lunch.
下面 女士们先生们
With that in mind, ladies and gentlemen,
让我们欢迎
would you please welcome into the studio -
实际上身处伦敦办公室
he's actually in his office in Londonr
但同时也在这根棍子上的
and yet he's also here on top of a stick -
鲍勃 吉尔道夫
it's Bob Geldof!
来向鲍勃问好
We're gonna say hello to Bob.
-我没法问好 -哈蒙德 他来了
- I can't say hello to Bob! - He's coming, Hammond.
-我还在转圈 -他在那儿
-I just go in circles! -It is!
各位 欢迎鲍勃 吉尔道夫
It's Bob Geldof, everybody!
鲍勃 你要去哪儿
Hello, Bob. Where have you gone?
鲍勃 我们在这边
Bob! We're over here, Bob!
-鲍勃 -转过来
-Bob! -Bob, we're over here!
-你们在哪儿 -他在那儿
-Where are you? -He's there!
鲍勃 你还好吗
Bob Geldof, how are you?
很好 圣诞快乐
Yes, happy Christmas!
噢 不好意思
Oh, ! Sorry!
-你圣诞过得还好吗 鲍勃 -哦 不 鲍勃
-Are you having a good Christmas, Bob? -Oh, no! Bob's...
观众们 鲍勃走丢了
Ladies and gentlemen, Bob Geldof is lost!
他跑错方向了
He's gone in the wrong...
詹姆斯 快过来
Oh, James May's coming to join in.
我来跟鲍勃聊聊
I'm coming to talk to Bob Geldof.
哇噢 梅和鲍勃亲嘴了
Whoa! May has kissed Bob Geldof!
-鲍勃 你好啊 -你给我让开
-Hello, Bob. How are you? -Get out of the way!
-我先四处看看 -别 直着走 鲍勃
-I'm travelling! -No, straight ahead, Bob.
鲍勃 别 左转 听我说 鲍勃
Bob, no. Left-hand down, Bob. No, Bob. Bob, you...
我刚刚是撞到某人的要害了吗
Have I just attacked somebody's knob?
鲍勃 别撞观众了
Bob, stop attacking the crowd!
他又要往哪儿跑
Now where's he going?!
鲍勃
Bob!
等等 让我来解救鲍勃
Right, I'll rescue Bob. Hold on.
鲍勃 一直往前 好的
Straight ahead, Bob. That's perfect.
-一直向前 -稍微向右转点
- Straight ahead. Straight. - A bit of right-hand down.
别 不要撞到树 别再撞圣诞树了
No, don't drive into it! Stop head-butting the tree!
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous!
圣诞老人和它的驯鹿呢？
Where's the reindeers and Santa Claus at?
噢 不 等等
Oh, no! Hang on a minute!
他毁了圣诞节
He's ruined Christmas!
他知道现在是圣诞节吗？
Does he know it's Christmas time at all?
好了 今晚 谢天谢地
Well, tonight, thank God it's him instead of us
是鲍勃 而不是我们把圣诞树撞倒了
knocking the Christmas tree over.
是的 他毁了我们的圣诞
Absolutely right. He's ruined it!
算了
Anyway, erm...
今年是赛车史上伟大的战役的
This year marks the 50th anniversary
50周年纪念
of the greatest battle in motorsport history.
故事开始于上世纪60年代
The story begins in the 1960s,
福特公司意识到 如果在赛车领域更有作为
when Ford realised that they could sell a lot more cars
民用车销量可以大幅提升
if they were a lot more successful on the racetrack.
所以他们制订了一个天才计划 但不幸的是
So they formulated a brilliant plan, but unfortunately...
这个计划最终折戟沉沙 没错吧 鲍勃
...it went disastrously wrong, didn't it, Bob?
福特公司知道 想要统治赛车界
Ford knew that if you wanted to rule in motorsport,
只要征服一项赛事就够了
there was only one race that mattered.
那就是致难致险的
The toughest and most dangerous of them all -
勒芒24小时耐力赛
the 24 Hours of Le Mans.
梅赛德斯车队的拉维发生了碰撞并引发爆炸
Levegh's Mercedes collides and blows up.
问题是 虽然身为巨头
The problem was, for all its might,
福特并不知道该如何才能赢得勒芒
Ford didn't have a clue how to win at Le Mans.
但是在意大利 有人知道
However, over in Italy, someone did.
上世纪60年代
In the early 1960s,
恩佐法拉利的车统治着赛车界
Enzo Ferrari's cars ruled sports-car racing,
尤其是勒芒
Le Mans especially.
60年代初
At the start of the decade,
他就在这项著名的高强度24小时耐力赛中
he had won the famous and gruelling 24-hour race
收获了三连冠
three times on the trot.
但是 公司当时却正面临着严重财政困难
However, the company was in deep financial difficulty,
所以当福特提出要全盘收购的时候
so when Ford offered to buy the entire business,
恩佐同意了
Enzo agreed.
起初 一切都很顺利
At first, all went well.
恩佐法拉利和福特公司的老大 亨利福特二世
Enzo Ferrari and the head of Ford, Henry Ford II,
很快就定下了1600万美金的价格
quickly settled on a price of $16 million.
1963年5月21日
And on May 21st 1963,
福特的管理层抵达马拉内罗来签署合同
Ford executives arrived in Maranello to sign the deal.
福特带了一大帮的精英律师
Ford turned up with an army of suits.
而恩佐法拉利对面而坐
Enzo Ferrari sat opposite them
身旁却只是镇上的小律师
with just the local town lawyer.
他们检查了合同 一切看似没有问题
They read the contract and all seemed well,
但突然间 法拉利的目光停了下来
but then, suddenly, Ferrari stopped
然后他拿出了那支有名的灌着紫色墨水的钢笔
and he took out his famous fountain pen full of purple ink,
从我手上的这份副本上大家可以看到
and as you can see from this accurate copy I have here,
他在这画了一个大大的感叹号并写道
he drew a big exclamation mark and he wrote,
不 这条不行
"No, that's no good!"
是什么让他这么生气呢
Now, what had angered him?
呐 是这里的这个条款
Well, it was this clause here.
是这样 恩佐法拉利想要保留
You see, Enzo Ferrari wanted to retain control
对于赛车部门的控制权
of the motorsport side of his business,
但这个条款却将它给了福特
but this bit effectively handed control to Ford.
在一通意语的喋喋谩骂之后
There followed a tirade of abuse in Italian,
恩佐法拉利跟他的律师说了句
after which, Enzo said to his lawyer
到饭点了
"Let's go and eat."
然后就在福特管理层的一片错愕当中
Then they got up and they simply walked out
起身离去
on the stunned Ford executives.
这事就这么黄了
That was that.
这一切都成了无用功
All of this for nothing.
回到底特律 亨利福特二世
Back in Detroit, Henry Ford II,
怒不可遏
apoplectic with rage,
召集了他的将领向他们下达了指令
gathered his lieutenants and issued the order:
给我造一辆能在勒芒上碾压法拉利的车
"Build me a car that will crush Ferrari at Le Mans."
想要在欧洲地盘上战胜法拉利
To beat Ferrari on European soil,
福特需要来自欧洲的专家
Ford needed European expertise,
所以他雇了一家小型的英国赛车厂
so he hired a small British motorsport company
就在这栋建筑里生火搭灶
that set up shop here, in this very building,
这里是离伦敦不远的斯劳工业区
on an industrial estate in Slough, just outside London.
而他们所面临的挑战是巨大的
And the challenges they faced were enormous.
他们需要造一辆能够跑到320公里以上的车
They had to build a car that would race at over 200mph,
这本身就已经前无古人了
which was something that had never been done before,
而且还要在勒芒耐力赛中坚持24个小时
and it had to be reliable for the 24 hours of the Le Mans race -
这其中将经历约9000次换挡
a race in which you changed gear 9,000 times
和4800多公里的全速行驶
and drove flat out for 3,000 miles.
更要命的是
And, as if that wasn't bad enough
他们只有十个月的时间
they only had ten months to do it.
在这样疯狂的时间表下
Out of that insane timetable emerged this.
福特GT诞生了
The Ford GT.
凭借其光滑的车身
Thanks to its sleek shape
和仅仅100公分的车身高度
and the body that stood just 40-inches tall,
它能如导弹般切割空气
it promised to cut through the air like a missile.
再加上一台4.2升的V8发动机
Add a 4.2L V8,
320公里的极速看似唾手可得
and the magic target of 200mph seemed in the bag.
问题是
The trouble is
赛车这东西 在上赛道之前
a racing car is just a collection of hopes and dreams
一切都是纸上谈兵
until it gets on the track.
福特为此吸取了惨痛的教训
And that's something that Ford learned in a very brutal way
在他们第一次在勒芒测试GT40的时候
when they took the GT40 to test at Le Mans for the first time.
第一次勒芒练习赛拉开了帷幕
And so to the first Le Mans practice session.
第一次亮相 重新命名的GT40很快
On its first outing, the renamed GT40 was fast,
但也惊人的不稳定
but it was also terrifyingly unstable,
在直道上后轮都会打滑
spinning its wheels on the straights.
我说的可不是在你刚刚出发的时候
I'm not talking about when you set off,
而是在时速270km/h的时候打滑
I mean it was happening at 170mph!
问题不是出在空气动力学上就是出在悬挂上
Now, the problem was either aerodynamics or suspension,
但他们永远也没机会弄明白
but they never found out,
因为那天晚些时候 那辆车以257公里的时速撞毁了
because, later that day, the car crashed at 160mph.
没关系 他们当然还有一辆备用车
Well, that was OK. They had a spare one, of course.
第二天 备用车也撞了
The next day, that crashed as well.
这时候据勒芒只有两个月了
Le Mans was just two months away.
历经千难万险
Against all odds
福特险险赶上了1964年的大赛
Ford got their act together in time for the 1964 race.
我们终于迎来了勒芒24小时耐力赛
The Le Mans 24 Hour Race at last,
和三辆崭新的福特GT
and three gleaming Ford GTs are present.
但是在比赛中
But during the race itself,
三辆车不是抛锚就是起火
all the cars broke down or caught fire,
这使得他们憎恨的对手法拉利
leaving bitter rivals Ferrari
再一次囊括了前三名
to take another one-two-three victory.
底特律那边
In Detroit
亨利福特决定他们明年会回来
Henry Ford decreed that they would be back next year
再战法拉利
to take on Ferrari again.
而领导这场战斗的人选
And to head up the campaign,
福特则想到了美国的赛车英雄
he turned to an American motorsport hero.
我叫卡罗尔谢尔比 我为性能车代言
My name's Carroll Shelby and performance is my business.
谢尔比原先是德州的一名养鸡户
Shelby was a former chicken farmer from Texas
平日里他需要服用硝化甘油来缓解他的心绞痛
who took nitroglycerin pills to keep his heart going.
但他作为车手和车队老板
But he'd also racked up countless victories
则赢下了无数的胜利
as a driver and team owner.
面对把GT40调教成冠军之车的任务
Given the task of turning the GT40 into a winner,
他派出了自己的王牌干将
he put his top man on the job.
接下来 您将看到的是肯迈尔斯
Coming up is Ken Miles,
全美最棒的跑车车手之一
one of the best sport-car drivers in America.
迈尔斯是一名来自伯明翰的
Miles was a former Second World War tank commander
前二战坦克指挥官
from Birmingham -
英国伯明翰 不是亚拉巴马那个
the one in England, not Alabama.
他以心直口快
He was renowned for speaking his mind
和善于调教赛车出名
and developing racing cars.
迈尔斯试了试这车
Miles took the car for a shakedown.
下车后 他对谢尔比和福特的高层说
Then he got out and he told Shelby and the Ford executives,
这什么破车
"It's bloody awful!"
然后他开始了工作
Then he got to work,
改进刹车 引擎
improving the brakes, the engine,
空气动力学设计 操控
the aerodynamics, the handling,
还有驯化这车高速时令人惊悚的不稳定性
and taming the car's terrifying high-speed instability.
不过 尽管他和他的团队服用安非他命
However, and even though he and his team took amphetamine
来使自己可以通宵工作
so that they could stay awake all night,
但研发一台能够参加勒芒的赛车
there simply wasn't time to develop the car properly
时间依然不够
for Le Mans.
虽然GT40的车速更快了
The GT40 may have been faster,
但它们却依然弱不禁风
but it was still fragile.
在1965年的比赛中
At the 1965 race,
有六辆车参赛 却无一完赛
six cars started, none finished,
而意大利人又一次羞辱了福特
and the Italians humiliated Ford once again.
数以百万的银子花了
So, untold millions of dollars had been spent
算上从这栋建筑里走出来的第一辆GT40
since the first GT40 emerged from this building here,
居然没有任何一辆能够顺利完赛
and yet not one car had even finished the race.
福特现在面临一个艰难的选择
So Ford now faced a difficult choice -
他要不向法拉利认输
he could throw in the towel against Ferrari
要不就得继续战斗
or he could fight on.
而他选择给他的勒芒团队
What he actually did was he had some business cards printed,
都打印了名片
and he distributed them to his Le Mans team.
名片上写着 你最好得赢
And on the cards it said, "You'd better win."
于是 一年之后
And so, a year later,
美国汽车巨头重回勒芒
the American giant returned to Le Mans
并将希望寄托在这辆车身上
with its hopes resting on this.
观众朋友们
OK, viewers,
这是我死前必开的历史性赛车清单上排名第二的
this is historic-race-car bucket-list moment number two,
因为这是一辆真正参加过
because this is an actual GT40
1966年勒芒比赛的GT40
that competed at Le Mans in 1966.
好了 别胡来 这车可是值1500万英镑
All right, don't go mad, May, it's worth 15-million quid.
管他呢 让引擎轰鸣起来吧
Sod it! Let's make some noise!
爽
Oh, yes!
在这辆新的GT40身上
In this new GT40,
肯迈尔斯跑了上千小时的测试
Ken Miles had racked up thousands of test hours.
使这辆车终于稳定下来
Now the car was no longer horribly unstable,
而是在338公里的时速下也稳如磐石
but would sit rocksteady at 210mph.
而且伯明翰的坦克指挥官
And the Brummie tank commander
有福特庞大的研发部门做后盾
had the backing of Ford's huge R&D department,
去改善这辆车极其糟糕的可靠性
who tackled the car's appalling reliability.
这车的刹车不会再在直道末端
The brakes no longer went into thermal shock
出现热衰减
at the end of the long straight.
引擎和变速箱也在电脑控制的试验台上进行了测试
The engine and transmission were run on a computerised test rig
模拟了整个勒芒24小时耐力赛的过程
that simulated the whole of the 24-Hour Le Mans race.
今天 这是F1测试的标配
Now, that's standard practice in Formula One today,
但是在1966年 这就是妖术啊
but in 1966 that was witchcraft.
这些小伙子们还真没含糊
They weren't mucking about, these blokes.
他们的对手也没含糊
But neither were the opposition.
在意大利这边 面对新出现的对手
Over in Italy, in response to the new threat,
法拉利的回应是这辆车
Ferrari produced this.
这辆代号P3的车 看上去和GT40一样光滑
Called the P3, it looked as sleek as a GT40.
而其95公分的车身高度 则比福特还低
And at just 37.4 inches tall, it was even lower.
冲啊
Avanti!
喔 亲娘啊
Whoo! Holy mother!
我最好在这条狭窄的道路上小心点
I best be a little bit careful on this narrow road.
它可是值2千万英镑
It's worth £20 million.
GT40拥有高达338公里每小时的最高时速
Where the GT40 boasted a top speed of over 210mph,
而P3最快只能开305公里每小时
the P3 maxed out at just 190.
但恩佐法拉利为了其他方面的优势
But Enzo Ferrari was willing to trade
愿意放弃绝对的速度
outright speed for gains elsewhere.
这辆车更轻 更灵活
The Ferrari was lighter, it was more agile.
法拉利认为它在弯道可以抹平速度上的差距
Ferrari reckoned he could make up the difference in the bends,
而且还不用经常进站加油
and he wouldn't have to stop so often for fuel.
一场大卫与歌利亚的战争就要打响
A David and Goliath battle was looming.
在1966年的勒芒比赛上 福特带来了一支大军
At the 1966 Le Mans race, Ford arrived with an armada -
8辆车 20吨的零件
eight cars, 20 tonnes of spares,
一队的世界级车手
and a squad of world-class drivers,
其中包括肯迈尔斯本人
including Ken Miles himself.
相比之下 法拉利只带了三辆P3
In comparison, Ferrari turned up with just a trio of P3s,
但是恩佐手中也有一张王牌
but Enzo had an ace up his sleeve -
当时毫无争议的世界最快车手
the undisputed fastest driver on the planet,
F1世界冠军约翰苏提斯
Formula One World Champion John Surtees.
他走过来对我说 约翰
He came to me and said, "John...
我们必须要战胜福特 去击败他们
we've got to beat the Fords. Go out and do it."
我目前认为只有一种策略能成功
I thought there was only one tactic -
让至少一辆车来当野兔
to have at least one car be the hare.
我说 听着 我不介意来当那个野兔
I said, "Look, I don't mind being the hare."
旗子一落下
"The moment that flag goes down,
我们需要有车能撒丫子就跑
we need to be - bang - off,"
试图引诱福特车手冒险追击
tempting the Ford drivers to perhaps overdrive a little bit.
如果能够让他们超负荷驾驶的时间足够长
If one could push them hard enough for long enough,
他们就自然更有可能
then there is more likelihood, obviously
把车开坏
of being able to break them.
计划订好了
The plan was set.
但是 就在开赛前 一切都变了
But, as zero hour approached, everything unravelled.
就在开赛前不久
Shortly before the race
我们得知他将不会参赛
we learned that he wasn't going to drive,
我们就此事询问了他
and we asked him about it.
是的 不幸被言中 我今天不会参赛了
Yes, unfortunately you've heard correct. I won't be driving.
这是为什么呢
What is the reason?
我想现阶段最恰当的表述
Well, I suppose it's best summed up at this stage
就是 政治原因
by saying "political reasons."
原因在于法拉利的车队经理
The problem was that the Ferrari team manager
自己玩了个政治手段
was playing his own political game.
他对于苏提斯不怎么感冒
He had no particular liking for Surtees,
并且提名另一位车车手
and he nominated another driver
去跑第一棒 去当野兔
to go out and start the race, to be the hare,
即便苏提斯是当时世界上最快车手
even though Surtees was clearly the fastest man available.
我一气之下就开车走了
And I just stormed away, drove back
直接跟老头掰了
and had it out with the old man.
意大利的报纸是这么写的
As the Italian papers put it,
他们放了一张我走出大门的照片并写到
they showed a picture of me walking out the gates and saying,
约翰苏提斯和恩佐分道扬镳
"The divorce of John Surtees and Enzo."
没有了苏提斯
With Surtees out of the way,
福特在排位赛中占据了前四
the Fords took the top four slots in qualifying.
随着时间的临近
And as the clock ticked down
亨利福特二世准备为比赛挥旗开赛
Henry Ford II prepared to drop the flag,
同时祈祷着 这一次
praying that, this time
他能够如愿复仇
he would get his revenge.
从法国勒芒为您带来的 勒芒24小时耐力赛直播
Live from Le Mans, France, it's the 24 Hours of Le Mans.
一开始 福特迅速取得了领先
At first, the Fords stormed into the lead.
但没过几个小时
But a few hours in,
形势就仿佛要重演64年和65年的悲剧
it was beginning to look like a depressing repeat of '64 and '65.
随着夜幕降临 法拉利的赛车 凭借着更好的灵活性
As night fell, the Ferraris, using their greater agility
和更高效的油耗
and their greater fuel efficiency,
排名上升到了第一第二位
were leading the race one-two.
8辆GT40中有4辆则无奈退赛
Four of the eight GT40s were out of the race altogether.
更糟糕的是
Worse still
福特的车手们被明令禁止冒险驾驶
the Ford drivers had strict orders not to go balls-out
以保护赛车
for fear of breaking the cars.
但是有一个人无视了禁令
But one man wasn't listening to those orders.
肯迈尔斯没有保留
Ken Miles put the hammer down,
他的圈速一圈比一圈快
set blistering lap times
帮助福特重夺领先优势
and retook the lead for Ford.
法拉利的车手们根本跟不上这种节奏
The Ferraris had no response to this crushing pace,
到了早上 他们抛锚的抛锚 撞车的撞车
and by morning, they had either broken down or crashed.
那个下午
That afternoon
亨利福特亲眼目睹了
Henry Ford watched his cars cruise home
他的车惊人的以包揽前三的排名从容地驶过终点
to a spectacular one-two-three finish.
第一名是二代福特GT
First place for the Ford GT Mk II,
这也是美国人第一次在勒芒取胜
and a first-time win for America at Le Mans.
福特在接下来的四届勒芒赛事中都取得了胜利
Ford would go on to win their next four Le Mans races.
但是那个为这支队伍付出的最多的人
But the man who had contributed so much to the team
却没能看到这些胜利
didn't get to see these triumphs.
肯迈尔斯在第一年胜利后仅两个月
Ken Miles was killed two months after their first win,
便在测试新GT40时不幸身亡
testing the latest GT40.
我们无法得知亨利福特在对飙法拉利的三年中
It's impossible to calculate how much Henry Ford spent
究竟花了多少钱
on his three-year campaign to break Ferrari,
有专家估计 最少的情况下
but experts reckon that, at the very least,
换算成今天的价格 也要3亿6千万英镑
in today's money, it was £360 million.
只因为跟暴脾气的意大利人发生了口角 就花这么多钱
Now, that's a big bill for settling a spat with an angry Italian.
但是想想我们从中的收获
But look what we got out of it -
史上最佳车型之一
one of the world's greatest cars.
精彩
Very good.
真精彩 非常棒
That was good. Very good.
-我恨你 -我知道
-I hate you. -I know.
不 我现在真心恨你
No, but I really hate you now
因为你去开了福特GT40 而我没有
cos you've driven a Ford GT40, and I never have.
下周你打算怎样
I mean what is it next week
去舔海莲娜 克莉丝汀森马
are you gonna lick helena christensen
听着
Look...
我确信GT40那车 如果你真想开也能开
I'm sure you could drive a GT40 if you really wanted to.
不行 我太高了
I can't, I'm too tall.
你的意思是太胖了吧
Yeah, you mean fat.
高
Tall.
横向的高吧
Horizontally tall.
听我说 别管是哪个维度
Well, listen, whatever dimension is the problem,
反正我就是开不了
I can't drive one.
随着这浓浓的失望
And on that terrible disappointment
今天的节目到此结束
it is time to end.
感谢各位的收看 晚安
Thank you so much for watching. Good night.